您瞧 父亲 我们以前就谈过这个
Look, father, we have been through all this before.
按我说的去做 小子
Do as I tell you, boy,
你这该死的不听话的小杂种
you damn, disobedient little bastard.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
这是我的生活! 我要按我的方式去过!
It's my life and I'm going to run it the way I like.
给我滚上去!
Get up out of it.
早上好!
Good morning!
Morning!
钓到什么了吗?
Caught anything?
哈哈!
Ha-ha!
还没呢
Not yet.
福尔摩斯 你到这儿来干什么?
Holmes, what on earth are you doing here?
来找你
Looking for you.
你继续吧 亲爱的朋友
Well, carry on my dear fellow,
别让我打扰了你
don't let me disturb you.
你究竟是来干什么的?
What on earth are you doing here?
来办一个案子
A case has brought me this way.
什么样的案子?
What sort of case?
报纸上管它叫做
The newspapers are calling it the
Boscombe溪谷之谜
Boscombe Valley mystery,
我想你读过有关的报道了吧?
I expect you've read something of it?
未曾耳闻
Not a word.
我好多天没看报纸了
I haven't seen a paper for days.
一位农场主 Cole McCarthy 澳大利亚人
A farmer, Cole McCarthy, Australian by birth
死在了他农场尽头的一个湖边
met his death by a mirror at the bottom of his farm.
他们似乎已经认定 这是一起严重的案件
They seem to have established a very serious case
指控凶手就是死者的儿子
against the son of the murdered man.
那块石头下有条大鱼
There's a big one just under that rock.
这么说是起谋杀案了?
So then it's a murder?
呃 估计是这样
Well, it's projected to be so.
当然在我有机会亲自调查之前
Of course I shall take nothing for granted
我是不会想当然的
until I've had a chance to look into it personally.
那是自然
Naturally.
我不想毁了你的假期
I don't wish to spoil your holiday
但我在想能不能说服你
but I was wondering if I could persuade you
跟我一起查几天案?
to join me for a couple of days?
当然可以
Well of course.
真的吗?
Are you sure?
我的荣幸
I shall be delighted.
那我们必须马上动身
Then we must move quickly,
当地火车35分钟之后出发
our local train leaves in 35 minutes.
您的水 先生
Your water, sir.
华生 这些新鲜空气会要了我的命
Watson, all of this fresh air will kill me.
嗯
Mmm.
似乎伦敦报业对此事兴趣不浓
Well, the London Press don't seem much interested,
没有很完整的报道
not very full accounts.
是的
Yes.
毫无用处
Useless.
报纸就看到这儿吧
So much for the London Press.
案子似乎再简单不过了
It all seems depressingly simple,
到底是什么让你对它产生了兴趣?
what persuaded you to take an interest in this case?
这个
This.
Boscombe溪谷一案
Boscombe Valley mystery.
审理中存在严重误导
There has been a grave miscarriage of justice.
事态紧急
The matter is urgent.
我们需要您的帮助
We need your help.
如能驾临 不胜欣幸 Alice Turner
Please come if you can, Alice Turner.
老天 谁是Alice Turner?
Good heavens, who is Alice Turner?
她是Turner先生的女儿
She is the daughter of Mr. Turner,
也是澳大利亚人 这整片庄园都是她家的
also Australian who owns this whole estate.
噢 这对于Turner小姐而言 这只是一个"谜团" 而不是一起谋杀
Oh, well it's a mystery, not murder to Miss Turner.
注意这个"我们"  华生 "我们需要您的帮忙"
Note the "we" Watson, we need your help.
如果说这是心底的呼唤
If ever there's a cry from the heart that is
那它已经跃然纸上了
that it leaps from the paper.
你见过这位女士了吗?
Have you seen this lady?
还没有
No, not yet.
你还记得一位叫Summerby的警官吗?
Do you remember a certain Sergeant Summerby?
Summerby?
噢 是的 那起西班牙纸币伪造案
Oh, yes, the case of the counterfeit Spanish dollars.
是墨西哥
Mexican.
一个讨人喜欢的家伙 很崇拜你的办案法方 对吧?
A pleasant fellow much admired your methods did he not?
也许这就是他升为督察的原因
Probably his reason for promotion to Inspector.
他负责这起案子
He is in charge of the case and it was he
就是他给我们安排了这个住处
who organized this accommodation for us.
我们?
Us?
你断定了我会来?
You presumed that I would come?
不 不是"断定" 华生
No, not presumed, Watson,
是"希望"  非常希望
hoped, very much hoped.
福尔摩斯先生
Well, Mr. Holmes
还有你 医生
and you, Doctor,
很高兴又再见到你们
it's a pleasure to see you again.
对你的升职谨表祝贺 督察
Congratulations on your promotion, Inspector.
谢谢 医生
Thank you, Doctor.
这通常是个安静的地区
It's a quiet district as a rule
不过依然是我自己的辖区
but nonetheless my own.
我叫了一辆马车在等着
I have a carriage waiting.
啊 哦!
Ah, oh.
这个被害的McCarthy
McCarthy, the murdered man
从Turner先生那里 租了一个叫Havely的农场
rented a farm called Havely from a Mr. Turner
Turner是当地最大的农场主之一
who is one of the largest London proprietors in this part of the country.
他在澳大利亚发的财
He made his money in Australia.
我想拥有同样在殖民地的经历
I presume that both being colonials
让他们会有很多共同之处
they had much in common.
我想是老朋友吧
Old friends, I believe.
Turner先生已经病了一段时间了
Well, Mr. Turner has been in failing health for some time.
他有个叫Alice的女儿?
He has a daughter called Alice?
是他的独女 非常迷人
An only child and a most charming one.
我们想Turner小姐 和McCarthy家的儿子是朋友吧?
We surmise that Miss Turner and the McCarthy boy are friends?
非常要好的朋友
Great friends.
是Turner小姐请我到这儿来的
It was Miss Turner who brings me here.
噢 我知道 福尔摩斯先生
Oh I know, Mr. Holmes,
坦白说吧 您来了我很意外
and to be quite honest with you I'm surprised you came.
这个案子其实非常清楚
The case is as plain as a flag staff
我接触得越多 就越觉得案情很明朗
and the more I get into it the plainer than it comes.
所以我提醒Turner小姐说
So I have warned Miss Turner that this time
这次就算是歇洛克.福尔摩斯先生
not even Mr. Sherlock Holmes
也不能让奇迹出现
will be able to work miracles.
这里的乡村景色真美
It's a beautiful countryside.
是的 的确如此 这是Boscombe溪谷
Yes, yes, indeed this is Boscombe Valley.
那边的谷底就是Boscombe湖
And over there at the bottom is Boscombe Mirror
也就是凶案发生的地方
where the murder took place,
一个宁静之地居然发生了如此悲剧
a peaceful place for a tragedy.
有目击者吗?
Any witnesses?
我就等你问这个问题 福尔摩斯先生
I expected that question, Mr. Holmes.
主要的目击者是William Crowder
The principle witness is William Crowder,
是Turner先生的猎场看守之一
one of Mr. Turner's gamekeepers.
就在我用完晚餐以后
It was after I had me dinner,
上星期一是...
last Monday it was, the...
六月三号
The third of June.
噢 噢 没错
Oh, that's right.
我现在养小雉鸡
Now I fed the young pheasants,
我们管它们叫小雉
ports we call them.
你当时正把生菜移到户外来种
You were planting out lettuces.
噢 是的
Oh, that's right,
我正在移植生菜
I was setting out some lettuces,
就是那边的那些
those lettuces over there.
突然我的小女儿Patience
When my little girl, Patience,
一路跑过来
she comes running up.
爸爸 爸爸 McCarthy父子在吵架
Dad, dad, the McCarthy's are fighting.
这不是第一次了
Well it won't be the first time.
别担心 Patience
Well, don't you worry about it, Patience,
那不关我们的事
it ain't no concern of ours.
去吧 进去吧
Go on, in you go.
那个McCarthy先生
That, Mr. McCarthy,
他的脾气...你知道啦
he has a temper that one, you know.
要是他认为有另一只枪
You know, if he thought another gun
在偷猎他瞄准的鸟
had poached his bird out shooting,
就会乱开一通把鸟吓走
he'd let fly in a real fury.
那小伙子也是这样吗?
Was the boy the same way inclined?
请不用给我倒牛奶
No milk for me, please.
不是的
No.
在我看来他不是这样的人
No, not that I've noticed anyway.
不 他看上去一直是个和气的孩子
No, he always seemed a nice enough boy.
他干了这样的事情让我很意外
I'm surprised him doing such a thing.
不过 话又说回来
But, then again,
他当时被激怒了
he was provoked.
毫无疑问 就是这样的
No doubt, who's to say.
你来告诉这两位先生接下来发生的事
You tell the gentlemen what happened next.
什么?
What?
你没有忘记你在聆讯作证时所说的话吧?
You haven't forgotten what you said in evidence at the inquest.
忘记?
Forgotten?
只要活着一天 我就不会忘记
I shant forget that day not so long as I live.
我把Patience打发回屋里找她的母亲
I just sent Patience into her mother
之后才仅仅移植了另一个苗木箱的生菜
and I hadn't planted out no more than another hour box,
Hugh McCarthy就跑了上来
when Hugh McCarthy come running up
活像见了鬼似的
looking like he'd seen a ghost.
我父亲遇到了一起严重的意外
My father's met with a terrible accident.
请跟我来 我需要你帮忙
Please come with me, I need your help.
他在哪?
Where is he?
在山下的湖边
Down by the Mirror.
他还活着吗?
Is he alive?
你跟我来
You just come along with me.
我把他带回到这儿来
I brought him back here
然后派我的妻子去找警察
and I sent me wife down to the track for the police.
那个男孩有没有说什么?
Did the boy say anything?
没有 没有 一声不吭
No, no, not a word.
他就坐在你坐的这个位置上
He just sat there where you are,
又哭又呜咽
sobbing and moaning
我一直盯着他
and I didn't take me eyes off him
直到他们来抓他  事实就是这样了
until they came for him, that's the truth.
你是不是彻底检查了那把枪
Did you examine the gun at all,
比如说枪托?
the butt for instance?
没有
No.
没有 没有专门检查
No, not especially,
枪上面有点泥
there was a bit of mud on it.
他擦过枪了
He wiped it.
呃 我可能是擦了枪
Well I might've done.
我是说这很自然 不是吗?
I mean it would've been natural wouldn't it?
McCarthy先生躺在那里 死了
There was Mr. McCarthy lying there dead
脑袋被砸瘪了
with his head bashed in.
驱赶黄蜂也不会搞成那样吧?
He hadn't got that way swatting wasps had he?
而你认为那个小伙子杀了他的父亲?
And you believe that the boy killed his father?
呃 我当然是这样想的 先生
Well, of course I do, sir.
我是说还能是谁呢?
I mean who else could've done it?
我能告诉你们的就这么多 先生们
I can tell you this much, gentlemen.
好吧 我是个猎场看守人 我知道
All right, now, I'm a gamekeeper all right
如果谁手里拿着一把枪
and when a man's got a gun in his hand
再不可思议的事情也会发生
strange things can happen.
我见过不少人
Oh, now I've seen men,
相当遵纪守法的人
quiet law abiding gentleman,
可要是把枪放到他们手里
you put a gun in their hands
就会变得近乎疯狂
they turn into near maniacs.
非常感谢 Crowder先生
Thank you so much, Mr. Crowder,
占用了你这么宝贵的时间
for giving so much of your valuable time.
噢 我很荣幸 先生们
Oh, it's been a pleasure gentlemen.
我不是第一次协助司法调查了
It's not the first time I've been able to help the cause of justice,
不 绝不是
no, not by a long shot.
呃 去年圣烛节的时候
All right, well last year at Candlemas time,
你还记得吧 督察?
you remember Inspector?
-不 我说错了 是两年前... -呃 我们得走了
-No, I'm a liar, it were two years ago. -Well, we must be on our way.
我是站在法律和秩序一方的 先生
Well, I'm on the side of law and order, sir,
督察会告诉您的
the Inspector will tell you that.
你的确是如此 Crowder
Indeed you are, Crowder.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见
Goodbye.
这些乡下人都一个样
They're all the same these country people.
要是有人听他们说
Once they get an audience
就会喋喋不休说个没完
they'll talk the hind leg off a donkey.
您要是跟我走的话
Now if you follow me
我会带您到案发现场去
I'll take you down to the scene of the crime.
暂时没这个必要
No need for the moment.
那倒是真的 在这种情况下确实没必要
That's very true, no need in the circumstances.
这是件不幸的案子 却很明朗
It's a sad case, but a pretty clear one,
气压很高
the glass is high.
天气晴朗
Weather set fair.
我要去探访James McCarthy
I shall like to call on James McCarthy.
要是您想去的话我可以安排
I can arrange it if you wish.
明天
Tomorrow.
还有一件事我得告诉您 福尔摩斯先生
One more thing I should tell you, Mr. Holmes.
那个小伙被控谋杀时
When the boy was charged with the murder,
他一点也不显得惊奇
he didn't appear in the least surprised.
事实上 他说这是他应得的
In fact, he said it was no more than his desserts,
这是他的原话
those were his very words.
算是认罪了吗?
A confession?
你也可以这样想
You might think so.
那他是不是也宣称了自己的清白?
Did he also protest his innocence?
是的
Yes.
不过罪犯总是这样说的 不是吗?
But then again, they always do don't they?
我想我们最好还是回旅馆去
I think we best be getting back to the hotel.
我还去庄园做些拜访
I have some calls to make on the estate.
那明天见
Until tomorrow then.
Boscombe Arms旅馆
Boscombe Arms.
那男孩说这是他应得的
The boy said he got no more than his desserts,
呃 这样说相当可疑
well that's a pretty suspicious remark.
我是说 在发生了这么多事之后
I mean, coming after such a damning series of events.
相反地 在目前这恰好是
On the contrary the brightest rips I can see
在云层中我能看到的最明亮的一线曙光了
in the clouds at present.
他话中流露出的悔悟
Self-approach contrition displayed by his remark
是一种健康心态的象征
appears to be signs of a healthy mind,
说明他不心虚
rather than a guilty one.
比这微小得多的证据 都曾把许多人送上了绞架
Many men have been hanged on far slighter evidence.
确实如此
So they have
许多人被错误地送上了绞架
and many men have been hanged wrongfully.
瞧 一只野鸡
Oh, look, a pheasant.
嗯 听这证词
Mm, witness.
James McCarthy说的
That's James McCarthy.
我和我的父亲进行了一次谈话
I had a conversation with my father,
言辞渐渐激烈起来
which led to high words,
差点就要吵开了
and almost to blows.
因为他的脾气渐渐难以控制
As his temper was becoming ungovernable,
我就离开了他 往山上走
I left him and went up the hill.
走出不到一百码
I hadn't gone more than a hundred yards
突然听到一声很可怕的呼喊
when I heard a hideous outcry,
使我马上往回赶
which caused me to run back again.
我发现我父亲躺在地上
I found my father
快要断气了
expiring on the ground
头部严重受伤
with his head terribly injured.
你回去的时候
Did you see anyone near your father
有没有看到你父亲的周围有什么人?
when you returned?
没有 一个人也没有
No, no one.
我不知道他是怎么受的伤
I have no idea how he came by his injuries.
他不是一个讨人喜欢的人
He was not a popular man,
但据我所知
but as far as I know
他没有什么健在的敌人
he had no active enemies.
对这点我只知道这么多
I know nothing further of the matter.
你父亲咽气之前 有没有跟你说起什么?
Did your father say anything to you before he died?
他咕哝了几句话
He mumbled a few words
但是我能听清的就是他提到了一只老鼠
but all I could catch was some allusion to a rat.
安静 肃静
Silence, be quiet.
一只老鼠?
A rat?
对此你有什么看法?
And what did you understand by that?
对我而言毫无意义
It conveyed nothing to me.
我觉得...
I thought,
我觉得他神志不清
well I thought he was delirious.
你和你父亲临终前的这次争吵
What was the point upon which you and your father
是关于什么事情的?
had this final quarrel?
我不想回答这个问题 先生
I should prefer not to answer that question, sir.
恐怕我得坚持这个要求
I'm afraid that I must press it.
我真的不可能告诉您
It really is impossible for me to tell you
但是我可以向您保证
but I can assure you that it had nothing to do
它与此后的悲剧无关
with the sad tragedy that followed.
是否有关要留待法庭来判断
That is for the court to decide.
我必须向你指出
I need hardly point out to you
你拒绝回答问题的行为
that your refusal to answer
在未来的可能进行的诉讼中
will prejudice your case considerably
将对你的案子
in any future proceedings,
十分不利
which may arise.
你可以坐下了
You may sit down.
陪审团的先生们
Gentlemen of the jury,
你们在这里是为了查清
you are here to discover the cause of death
William McCarthy先生的死因
of Mr. William McCarthy
然后宣布你们的裁决
and thereafter to deliver your verdict.
你们已经听到这起罪案的相关事实了
You have heard the facts of this crime
我相信这些事实让案情相当明朗
and I believe they make the situation very clear.
James McCarthy对他父亲的死的供述
Mr. James McCarthy's account of his father's dying
就算退一步来说也是很奇怪的
is singular to say the least.
他拒绝提供他与其父最后对话的细节
His refusal to give any details of their last conversation
这对他极为不利
must go very much against him.
在我看来  做出故意谋杀的裁决
The verdict of willful murder seems to me to fit
与我们所听到的事实是相符的
the facts we have heard.
希望我说得够清楚了
I hope I make myself clear.
那么就是故意谋杀了
So willful murder it was.
难以置信
Monstrous.
呃 这小伙子的确也是自找的
Well the boy did rather ask for it.
我亲爱的华生 你难道没发现
My dear Watson, don't you see that both you and the coroner
你和验尸官都没能
have been some pains
指出对这位年轻人最有利的一点吗?
to single out the strongest points in the young man's favor?
你没发现你们都认为他
Don't you see that you're terribly giving credit
想象力过于丰富或过度缺乏吗?
for much too much imagination or too little.
说太缺乏 是因为他没能编造出一个吵架理由
Too little, if he could not invent a quarrel
来博得陪审团的同情
which would give him the sympathy of the jury.
说太丰富 是他居然故意说出
Too much, if he evolved from his own
死亡与一只老鼠有关
inner consciousness anything so outr
这么有悖常理的说辞
as a dying of reference to a rat.
这些乡村验尸官总以为
Well, these country coroners do think
-自己是什么万能的神明 -那完全是不光彩的
they're little tin pot gods. It's an absolute scandal.
不不不
No, no, no.
我处理这个案子必须以这个观点为基础
I shall approach this case from the point of view
那就是这位年轻人所说的话是真的
of what this young man says is true.
我们来了一位访客
We have a visitor.
我们年轻的委托人到了
Our young client has arrived.
请进
Come in.
您来了我太高兴了 福尔摩斯先生
I'm so glad you've come, Mr. Holmes.
我叫Alice Turner
I'm Alice Turner.
这位是我的朋友和同事 华生医生
And this is my friend and colleague, Dr. Watson.
-华生医生 久仰 -Turner小姐
Dr. Watson, of course. Miss Turner.
就是您用那么充满趣味的笔触
It is you who have written down
把福尔摩斯先生的一些案子
some of Mr. Holmes' cases
记录了下来
in such an interesting way.
你瞧 我了解您的一切 福尔摩斯先生
You see I know all about you, Mr. Holmes
还有您的过人成就
and your wonderful success.
您知道我们此刻是多么需要您吗
If you knew how much we need you now,
不过您对已发生的事有所了解吧?
but do you yet know anything of what happened?
请坐 Turner小姐
Please sit down Miss Turner.
Summerby督察已经告诉过我一些情况
Inspector Summerby has told me something of it.
噢 是的 那位督察
Oh, yes, the Inspector.
他把您的地址给了我
He gave me your address.
他是个不错的人 不是吗?
He's quite a kind man, isn't he?
不过他不明白
But he doesn't understand.
他又怎么能明白呢? 他是位警察啊
How could he, he's a policeman.
福尔摩斯先生 我知道这不是James干的
Mr. Holmes, I know that James didn't do it.
我知道的
I know it and
而我也希望您在开始调查的时候 能抱着同样的看法
I want you to start your work knowing it too.
对此您永远也不要怀疑
Never let yourself doubt upon that point.
你认识James McCarthy很久了吗?
Have you known James McCarthy a long time?
是的 认识他一辈子了
Yes, all my life.
我们打小就认识
We have known each other since we were children,
他心肠很软 连一只苍蝇都不会去伤害
but he's too tender-hearted to hurt a fly.
对于那些真正了解他的人来说 这项指控实在是荒唐
This charge is just absurd to anyone who really knows him.
那我希望我们可以还他清白
Well, I hope that we may clear him.
我会尽我所能的
I shall do all I can.
但是从您已经听到的来看
But from what you've heard already,
您不觉得他是无辜的吧?
do you not think he's innocent?
我觉得那是有可能的
I think it is probable.
我知道我的朋友还有所怀疑
I don't know my friend is so convinced.
我想福尔摩斯先生的这个结论
I think that Mr. Holmes is being a little,
下得有点太快了
a little quick in his conclusions.
但您是对的
But you are right.
噢 我知道您是对的
Oh, I know that you are right.
James永远不会这么做
James never did it.
对于他不愿向验尸官谈起的
This quarrel with his father,
他与他父亲之间的争吵
which he would not talk about to the coroner,
你是否有所了解?
do you know anything of it?
我相信那是因为此事涉及到我
I believe it was because I was concerned in it.
哪个方面?
In what way?
现在不是遮遮掩掩的时候
It is no time to hide anything now.
James和他的父亲
James and his father
因为我有过很多争执
had many disagreements about me.
McCarthy先生很希望
Mr. McCarthy was very anxious
我们能够结婚
that there should be a marriage between us,
但是James和我之间的爱
but James and I have always loved each other
一直都是兄妹般的感情
like brother and sister.
当然我们近来不常见面
Of course we haven't seen so much of each other lately.
我离家到寄宿学校上学 也有好几年了
I have been away at boarding school for some years
而James一直在利物浦上学
and James has been studying in Liverpool.
他只有22岁而且生活阅历不多
He is only 22 and has seen very little of life
所以 呃 我想 现在他还不想结婚
and well, I suppose he does not  wish to do anything like that just yet.
于是他们就有了争吵
So there were quarrels.
而我想这次也是一样
And this, I'm sure, was one of them.
你多大了 Turner小姐?
How old are you, Miss Turner?
我18了 就快19岁了
I am 18, quite nearly 19.
就像你所说的
As you say,
这不是遮遮掩掩的时候
this isn't a time to hide anything.
你有没有爱上James McCarthy?
Are you in love with James McCarthy?
是的 我爱他 福尔摩斯先生
Yes, I am, Mr. Holmes,
非常爱他
very much in love.
再没有其他人...
There is no one else
以后也不会有 即使...
and never will be even if,
那他对你的感情呢?
And he with you?
哦 我想也是吧
Oh, I think so.
我希望如此
I hope so,
但我怎么敢肯定
but how should I know for sure?
我们从未谈起过婚事
We have never discussed marriage.
你的父亲赞成这样的联姻吗?
Was your father in favor of such a union?
不 他反对
No, he was adverse to it.
除了McCarthy先生 没人赞成这桩婚事
No one but Mr. McCarthy was in favor of it.
谢谢你对我们如此坦诚
Thank you for being so frank with us.
要是我去拜访你父亲的话
If I was to visit your father
我能见到他吗?
could I see him, please?
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
医生不许他会客
The doctor has forbidden any visitors.
我很抱歉 我们不知道他病得这么厉害
Oh, I'm sorry, we did not know he was so ill.
我的父亲身体一直比较虚弱
My father has never been strong
不过这件事让他彻底地垮了
but this has broken him completely.
噢 他卧床不起
Oh, he has taken to his bed
Willow 医生说他已经行将就木了
and Dr. Willow says that he's a wreck
精神也垮了
and his nervous system is shattered.
我几乎没法离开他
Well I can hardly leave him
要不我就会去火车站接您了
or I would've been at the railway station to meet you.
呃 您要知道
Well, you see,
从前在澳大利亚认识我父亲的人
Mr. McCarthy was the only man alive
就只剩下McCarthy先生了
who had known dad in the old days in Australia.
澳大利亚?
Australia?
在维多利亚州的矿上 金矿
In Victoria at the mines, the gold mines,
父亲就是在那里发的财
that's where dad made all his money.
你帮了我的大忙
You have been of material assistance to me.
您会去探望James?
Will you be able to see James?
明天
Tomorrow.
告诉他我知道他是无辜的
Tell him that I know him to be innocent.
我会的
I will.
您能不能把这个给他?
Could you give him this?
当然可以
Of course.
您要是有消息会告诉我的 对吧?
And if you have any news you will tell me?
我现在得回家了
I must go home now.
我留下家父在家睡觉
I left my father asleep but if he awakes
不过要是他醒了而我又不在那儿 他会心烦的
and I'm not there he'll be upset.
再见
Goodbye.
再见 上帝保佑您调查顺利
Goodbye and God help you in your undertaking.
早上好 督察
Morning Inspector.
我可以单独见他吗?
May I see him alone, please?
可以的 福尔摩斯先生
As you wish, Mr. Holmes.
但是记住这个人还在羁押中
But remember this man is on remand
被指控故意谋杀
accused of willful murder
您都知道
and as you well know
在这样的环境下这样的一个人
such a man under such circumstances
-是不可能说真话的 -噢 谢谢你的忠告
-isn't likely to speak the truth. -Oh, thank you for your good advice.
James McCarthy
James McCarthy,
我是歇洛克.福尔摩斯
my name is Sherlock Holmes.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
我怎么才知道是不是真的?
How should I know that?
你和警方的督察一起来的
You came with the police Inspector,
我看见他在外面了
I saw him out there.
我是应Turner小姐的要求来的
I'm here at the request of Miss Turner.
对不起 福尔摩斯先生
I am sorry, Mr. Holmes.
近来我学会了不要相信任何人
Lately I've learned to trust no one.
恐怕您来迟了
I'm afraid you've come too late.
他们已经断定
They've already made up their minds
我是有罪的了
that I am guilty.
我就没有
Well, I have not.
这是死因庭 (由死因裁判官主持 裁决死者的死因)
The Coroner's court.
噢 是的 死因庭的陪审团
Oh yes, and the Coroner's jury,
对调查的事实一无所知
innocent to inquire into the facts.
他们坐在那里却没有在审案
They do not sit in judgment.
呃 我怎么才能帮上忙?
Well, how can I help you?
我要你告诉我准确的事发经过
I'd like you to tell me exactly what happened.
让我们在这里坐下来 这样可以小声细谈而不会被偷听
Let's sit down over here where we  can talk quietly and not be overheard.
我该从哪儿说起呢?
Where shall I start?
随便你
You choose.
呃 我在利物浦上学大约有三年了
Well, I've been studying in Liverpool for some three years.
我父亲非常希望
My father was most anxious
我能得到学术方面的资格
I should have some academic qualifications.
就在那一天
It was on that day,
六月三号 我回到了家
June the 3rd that I returned home.
你父亲当时正在等你吗?
Was your father expecting you?
不 不 不完全是
No, no, not exactly.
他知道我可以放几天假
He knew I was due for a few days holiday,
不过不知道确切的日期
but not the exact date.
我们当地的客车把我 从村子带回了农场
Our local carrier took me up to  the farm from the village.
欢迎回家 很高兴见到你回来 James少爷
Welcome home, nice to see you back, Master James.
噢 回来真好 George
Oh, it's nice to be back, George.
嗨 Stan Stan?
Hey, Stan, Stan?
我父亲在屋里吗?
Is my father in the house?
不 不 大概五分钟之前出去了
No, no, went off about five minutes ago,
好像有什么心事
looked as though he had something on his mind.
好的 George
All right, George.
你待会儿要用小马吗?
Will you be wanting pony later?
不 不 我明天再骑
No, no, I'll ride tomorrow.
我也许该带上把枪
I might have a gun,
看能不能打上几只兔子
see if I could pull a few rabbits.
来了很多狩猎的
Plenty shooting,
把这地方挤满了
place is crawling with them.
欢迎回家
Welcome.
你好 父亲
Hello, father.
James?
你在这儿干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我回来过几天 就这样
I'm just here for a few days that's all.
呃 我不想你到这下面来
Well, I don't want you down here
所以赶紧上去
so get up out of it,
离得远远的 明白了吧?
keep away from it, do you understand?
好...为什么呢?
Yes, why?
关你屁事!
None of your damn business!
按我说的做就好了!
Just do as you're told.
James
James.
瞧 既然你都来了
Look, now you are here
就去Turner家一趟
get over the Turner's place
告诉那女孩你要娶她
and tell that girl you'll marry her.
我不干
I'll do no such thing.
-您瞧 父亲 我们以前就谈过这个 -按我说的去做!
-Look, father, we have been  through all this before. -Do as I tell you,
你这该死的不听话的小杂种
you damn, disobedient, little bastard.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
-把枪给我! -这是我的生活!
-Give me the gun! -It's my life and
我要按我的方式去过!
I'm going to run it the way I like.
好吧 该死的东西!
All right, damn you!
我要把你赶出家门
I'll throw you out.
我要毁了你
I'll ruin you.
你走着瞧
You'll see.
现在给我滚开!
Now get off out of it!
我还没走几步
I had hardly gone any distance at all
就听到一声可怕的尖叫
when I heard a terrible scream.
我往回跑
I ran back down
发现我父亲侧躺着
and found my father lying on his side.
你有没有看见别人?
Did you see anyone else?
没有
No one.
到处都没有动静吗?
No movement anywhere?
没有 我光顾着看我的父亲了
No, my attention was entirely on my father.
他伤得很厉害
He was terribly wounded.
你不肯把你和你父亲这次争吵的内容
You would not tell the coroner
告诉验尸官
about this quarrel with your father.
这是我的私事
It was something private.
又不关他的事
It was no business of his.
不是因为和你父亲的这次冲突
Was it not because this confrontation
会对你不利吗?
with your father might seem to incriminate you?
不 不 是因为关系到Alice
No, no, it was because it concerned Alice.
这个不关验尸官或是其他人的事
It was no business of the coroners or anyone else's.
我不想她的名字在法庭上 被人随意谈论
I wasn't going to have her name bandied about in the courtroom.
你知道Alice爱着你吧 James
You do know that Alice loves you, James
而且相信你是无辜的
and believes you to be innocent.
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
在这个可怕的地方
The thought of her love and her faith in me
要不是想起了她对我的爱和信任
has kept me in some sort of sanity
我早就疯掉了
in this horrible place.
然而你却不想依你父亲的心愿去娶她?
And yet you had no wish to marry her as your father so clearly wished?
也许你不爱她?
Perhaps you did not share her love?
我爱她
I did.
我真的爱她 福尔摩斯先生
I do, Mr. Holmes,
我爱Alice Turner
I love Alice Turner.
我...我为她着迷
I, I adore her,
我拜倒在她的裙下 但是...
I worship the very ground she treads on, but...
然而?
And yet?
我不能向她求婚 因为...
I could not ask her to marry me because,
因为我已经结婚了
because I was married already.
你不觉得最好把事情都告诉我吗?
Don't you think you'd better tell me about it?
我刚到利物浦上学的时候
When I first started studying in Liverpool
我父亲给了我相当一笔零用钱
my father gave me a very generous allowance.
也许太大方了 对我没有好处
Perhaps too generous for my own good.
我变得很放荡
I became very wild
交上了一伙损友
and fell in with a bad set of people.
于是在醉酒后的疯狂状态中
And in a fit of drunken madness
我在婚姻注册处
I went through a form of marriage
和一个比我大得多的女人登记结了婚
in a register office to a woman much older than I was,
一个酒吧女招待
a barmaid.
那时我几乎没怎么跟Alice见面
I hardly ever saw Alice at that time.
当然我也不能跟我父亲说
Of course I couldn't tell my father.
他肯定会把我赶出家门
He would certainly have thrown me out
他常这样威胁我
as he'd so often threatened.
是的 我肯定他会这样做的
Yes, I'm sure he would.
你知道
Have you any idea
谁会这么残忍地杀害你的父亲吗?
who would've killed your father so brutally?
不管怎么样 一个也没有
None whatsoever.
你知道我一日又一日地
Do you know I go over the scene
反复在脑海里重现那个场景
day after day after day in my mind.
但我和所有其他人一样没有头绪
But, I am as puzzled as everyone else is.
不要放弃希望
Don't give up hope.
谢谢 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯先生?
Oh, oh, Mr. Holmes?
怎么了?
Yeah?
这与案件没有什么关系
It hardly concerns all this business
但是也许我该告诉你
but perhaps I should tell you.
这桩祸事也许也有些好处
Some good has come out of this evil.
因为我被关进了这里
Since I've been in here
我收到了跟我结婚的那女人捎来的消息
I received a message from the woman I married
她在报纸上看到我惹上了大麻烦
who has read in the newspapers that I am in serious trouble
而且有可能被绞死
and likely to be hanged.
她写信说她其实已经
She wrote that she had a husband already
跟Bermuda造船厂的一个人结了婚
in the Bermuda dockyard.
老天!
Good heavens!
所以我们之间已经没有任何法律约束了
So, there is no legal tie between us.
要是我以前知道就好了
If only I had known before.
你告诉我是对的
You were right to tell me.
可怜的家伙
Poor fellow.
被他父亲如此责备 肯定让他发狂
Must've been maddening to be upbraided by his father
责备他不肯做一件
for not doing something
其实他是如此渴望去做的事情
he would give his very eyes to do.
要是他是无辜的
If he's innocent,
那是谁干的?
who did it?
没错
Indeed.
呃 也许我可以帮忙
Well perhaps I can help.
你不在的时候我并非完全无所事事
I've not been entirely idle in your absence.
审讯中 法医的证词里说到
Now in the surgeon's deposition of the inquest it states
左后部第三块顶骨
that the posterior third of the left parietal bone
和枕骨的左半边
and the left half of the occipital bone
都被钝器击碎了
were shattered by blows from a blunt weapon.
就是这里 在后面
Now that's here now behind
但是证据表明
but the evidence states
他们争吵的时候是面对面的
that they were quarreling face to face.
这个推理非常精彩 华生
That's a very nice piece of deduction, Watson.
谢谢
Thank you.
但却没有什么作用
But hardly a valid one.
McCarthy在女孩跑开的时候
McCarthy could've easily turned his back
很有可能正好转过身去
the moment the girl had run off.
但我很高兴你开始
But I'm so glad that you're coming around
用我和Turner小姐的角度去思考了
to my way of thinking and Miss Turner's.
那小伙子是无辜的
The boy is innocent.
福尔摩斯 你是硬把这话往我嘴里塞啊
Now, Holmes you're putting words in my mouth,
我并没有那样说过
I didn't say that.
不过你有那样想过 一点点
But you're thinking it just a little.
这双靴子就是主人被杀的时候穿的 先生
These boots were the ones the master  was wearing at the time he was murdered, sir.
那以后我当然是把它们都弄干净了
I've cleaned them off since, of course.
那双...那双是James少爷穿的
Those, those are a pair of Master James's.
他上次新买的
He bought them new last (unintelligible).
谢谢 George 我们现在到湖边去
Thank you, George, now let's get onto the Mirror.
就是这里 福尔摩斯先生
This is the place, Mr. Holmes.
您还可以看到血迹
You can still see traces of the blood.
请你们不要踩进来好吗?
Please, would you keep clear of this area?
你们为什么要到下面来 督察?
Why did you enter the Mirror, Inspector?
用耙子找过东西
Fished them out with a rack,
我以为里头应该有武器之类的东西 或是其他的线索
thought there might be some  weapon thrown there or some other trace.
要是我能在他们之前到达这里就好了
If only I'd been here before they came
他们就像一群水牛 把所有的痕迹都搅乱了
like a herd of buffalo and wallowed all over it.
应该是猎场看守人和他那一伙人
This must be the gamekeeper and his gang.
这些足迹是小McCarthy的
These tracks are young McCarthy's
还有这些
And these.
他走了两次
Twice he walked.
他转了回来
He turned.
有一次他是跑来的
Once he ran
所以鞋印更深些
so the soles of the feet are deeply marked,
而脚后跟的印痕却几乎看不见
the heels are hardly visible.
这个证实了他的说法
That would bear out his story he ran
他看见他的父亲躺在地上就跑了过来
when he saw his father on the ground.
这个我也说过
(unintelligible).
他父亲就在这里来回踱步
The father paced up and down right here.
我们在这里找到了什么?
What have we here?
脚尖印
Tiptoes.
方头的鞋印 很不寻常的靴子
Square toes most unusual boots.
这位"方鞋头先生"从哪里来的呢?
Where did mister square toes come from?
福尔摩斯可以成为一种罕见的大型警犬
He'd a made a rare bloodhound Mr. Holmes.
这是个相当有趣的案子
It has been a case of considerable interest.
来吧
Come.
谢谢 George
Thank you, George.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
能不能帮我送一下这张条子?
Would you deliver this note?
好的 先生 没问题
Yes, sir, indeed.
马上去
Right away.
这会让你感兴趣的 督察
This may interest you Inspector.
这就是谋杀的凶器
The murder was done with it.
我看不到任何痕迹
I can see no marks.
没有痕迹
There are none.
那你又是怎么知道的?
Well, how do you know then?
草长在它的底下
The grass was growing under it.
说明它几天前还不在那儿
It had only been there a few days.
这与伤口相吻合
It corresponds with the injuries.
那凶手呢?
And the murderer?
他是一个高个子 左撇子
He's a tall man, left handed,
右腿有些瘸
limps with the right leg,
穿着厚底方头的狩猎靴
wears thick-soled shooting boots with square toes,
抽印度雪茄 用的是雪茄烟嘴
smokes Indian cigars, uses a cigar holder
口袋里还有一把用钝了的削笔刀
and carries a blunt pen knife in his pocket.
您真是了不起 福尔摩斯先生
You're a brilliant man, Mr. Holmes,
我真希望我有您这样的脑子
and I wish I had your brains.
您的理论非常好
Your theories are all very well
不过我还是不能相信
but I'm still not convinced.
这次不
Not this time.
我们要对付一个顽固的英国陪审团
We have to deal with a hardheaded British jury.
呃 你已经得到机会了 督察
Well, you've had your chance, Inspector.
我是一个实际的人 福尔摩斯先生
I'm a practical man, Mr. Holmes,
我无法在这乡村里转悠
I cannot undertake to go around the country
寻找一个左撇子男人
looking for a left-handed gentleman
还是瘸腿的
with the gamey leg,
我会成为Cheshire郡的笑柄
unless I become the laughing stock of Cheshire.
我们会知道的
We shall see.
你用你的方法
You work your method,
我用我的
I shall work mine.
现在让我们来研究一下早晨的工作
Now, let us take this morning's work.
我对地面的检查
From my examination of the ground
让我获得了
I gained details
关于罪犯特征的一些细节
as to the personality of the criminal.
唔 哈
Uh-huh.
但是你是怎么知道的?
But how?
你了解我的方法
You know my method.
它以对不起眼的事物的观察为基础
It's founded on the observance of trifles.
呃 我知道你从他的步幅长度
Well, his height I know you might roughly judge
能大概估算他的身高
by the length of his stride,
从他的足迹判断出他的靴子 可这个人是没有名字的
his boots by his traces but the man's nameless.
他右脚的足迹 总是比左脚的清楚
The impression of his right foot was always left distinct than that of the left.
为什么? 因为他是跛足的
Why? Because he limped.
他是个左撇子
He's left-handed,
因为这一击来自死者的正后方
the blow was delivered from immediately behind him
而他是靠着左边站着的
yet he was on the left-hand side.
华生
Watson.
他肯定是个左撇子 当然了
He must've been a left-handed man, of course.
在父子俩吵架的时候
He stood behind that tree
他就站在那棵树后面
during the confrontation between father and son.
他甚至还抽了烟
He even smoked.
抽烟?
Smoked?
雪茄烟灰
Cigar ash.
一种印度雪茄
An Indian cigar.
你记得我的专著吧
You will remember my little monograph
关于各色烟灰
on the subject of ashes from pipe,
雪茄 香烟和烟草
cigar and cigarette tobacco.
要是我没记错的话 有一百种不同的类型
One hundred different varieties if I remember.
一百四十种 谢谢 华生
One hundred and forty, thank you, Watson.
发现了烟灰之后
Having discovered the ash,
我又发现了烟头
I discovered this stump
那人把它扔在了苔藓之中
which the man had thrown among the moss.
在鹿特丹卷制的一种印度雪茄
An Indian cigar rolled in Rotterdam.
你会注意到
You'll notice
烟头没有被他放进过嘴里
that the end has not been in his mouth
所以他使用的是雪茄烟嘴
so he used a cigar holder.
末端是切掉的而不是咬掉的
The tip has been cut off, not bitten,
但切口不是很平整
but the cut is not a clean one,
所以我推测他有一把钝的小刀
so I deduced a blunt penknife.
你真了不起
You're amazing.
这个垂死的人所咕哝的话中
Among the words mumbled by the dying man.
小McCarthy能够听清的唯一字眼
The only word that young McCarthy could understand
就是"老鼠"
was the word rat.
老鼠 嗯
Rat, hmm.
非常古怪
Most curious.
跟我来
Come with me.
现在
Now.
你怎么读这个词?
What do you read?
一只老鼠 (发音为:啊拉特)
A rat.
现在呢?
And now?
巴勒-拉特  巴勒拉特
Balla-rat, Ballarat.
这就是死者所说的那个词
That is the word the man uttered.
澳大利亚
Australia.
来自巴勒拉特的某个人 巴勒拉特因何出名?
Someone from Ballarat, what is Ballarat known for?
金矿
Goldfield.
Turner小姐说她父亲在金矿区
Miss Turner said that her father had met McCarthy
结识了McCarthy
on the Goldfield.
凭着这些信息我知道方向之所在了
I see the direction, which all this points.
一个来自巴勒拉特的澳大利亚人
An Australian from Ballarat
一个住在这个地区的人
and one who is at home in the district.
要是我没有搞错的话 他来了
Unless I'm very much mistaken, he's here.
John Turner先生来了
Mr. John Turner.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
华生医生
Dr. Watson.
我女儿说你们住在这里
My daughter told me you were lodging here.
你收到我的便条了?
Did you get my note?
是的 是的
Yes, yes,
内容是到这里来以避免一起丑闻
something about coming here to avoid a scandal.
总好过在你府上见面
Better than meeting up at the hall,
人们会议论纷纷的
people might talk.
你干嘛想见我?
Why do you wish to see me?
噢 是的
Oh, yes.
我知道了所有你和McCarthy之间的事情
I know all about you and McCarthy.
我的朋友华生会记下一些事实
My friend Watson will jot down a few facts.
我保证除非很有必要
I promise it will not be used
否则我不会利用它们
unless it is absolutely needed.
请坐下
Do sit down.
你不了解那个死鬼McCarthy
You didn't know the dead man McCarthy.
他是魔鬼的化身
He was a devil incarnate.
是上帝保佑 你们才没有落入
God keep you out of the clutches
一个像他这样的人的魔爪之中
of a man such as he.
我被他玩弄于鼓掌已经很多年了
His grip has been upon me these many years
他毁掉了我的生活
and he's blasted my life.
我要先告诉你 我是怎么被他控制的
I'll tell you first how I came to be in his power.
那是60年代 在矿区
It was in the early 60's at the diggings.
那时我还是一个小伙子
I was a young chap then,
热血沸腾 莽莽撞撞
hot blooded and reckless.
呃 我没什么运气
Well, I had no luck with me claim,
于是就上了梁山
took to the bush and came what you'd call
成了你们所说的路匪
a highway robber.
我们有一小伙人
There was a little gang of us
过着一种疯狂自由的生活
who lived a wild free life of it.
不时抢劫一个车站
Sticking up a station from time to time
或是在路上打劫从矿区来的货车
or stopping the wagon on the road from the diggings.
他们管我叫"巴勒拉特的黑杰克"
They called me Black Jack of Ballarat.
我想那里的人至今还记得
I believe they still remember the Ballarat gang
"巴勒拉特帮"
in the colony.
货车司机就是McCarthy
The wagon driver was McCarthy
而我饶了他一命
and I spared him.
滚!
Get out of it!
继续 跑啊!
Go on, shift!
别烦着我 快点!
Do a (unintelligible), fast!
我们拿着金子跑了
We got away with the gold.
Mac和我都成了有钱人
And Mac and I were wealthy men
爬到了梦想的巅峰
beyond the dreams of Everest.
我们...
There was...
我们成了悬赏通缉的对象
There was a price on our heads.
我决定到英格兰来
I decided to make for England.
我决心安定下来
I determined to settle down
过一种平静而受人尊重的生活
to a quiet and respectable life.
我买下了这处庄园
I bought this estate
包括这整个村子 甚至这个旅馆
that included the whole village even this inn is mine.
我开始用我的钱做一些好事
I set myself to do a little good with my money
对我所作所为做出弥补
to make up for the way in which I'd earned it.
我结了婚而我的妻子年纪轻轻就去世了
I married and then my darling wife died young.
她给我留下了亲爱的小Alice
She left me my dear little Alice.
你可以说我是个幸福的人
I was a happy man you might say,
直到McCarthy控制了我
until McCarthy laid his grip upon me.
他一路跟踪我
He followed my trail,
他刚到这儿来的时候
when he first came here,
还光着脚丫 衣不遮体
he'd hardly a coat to his back or a boot to his foot.
"我们来了 杰克" 他说
"Here we are, Jack," he said,
"你可以收留我们"
You can have the keeping of us,
"我和我的小男孩"
me and my little boy,
"要是你不愿意..."
and if you don't,
"英格兰可是个法制国家"
England is a fine law-abiding country
"警察总是随便就能找到一个"
and there's always a policeman handy.
我就只好束手待毙 被他敲诈
I was a sitting duck for blackmail.
根本摆脱不了他
There was no shaking him off,
没完没了
there was no rest,
不得安宁
no peace,
不能忘却
no forgetfulness.
无论我去到哪里
Turn there I would,
都能看到他那张狡猾狞笑的脸
there was his cunning, grinning face at me elbow.
他一定要得到他想得到的东西
Whatever he wanted he must have
而不管他要什么
and whatever it was
我都得无条件地给他
I gave him without question.
土地 金钱 房子
Land, money, houses
直到最后他又提出了一个我不能满足的要求
until at last he asked the thing I could not give.
他想要Alice
He asked for Alice.
他的儿子和我的女儿一起长大
His son and my girl had grown up.
他知道我身体不佳
He knew I was in weak health.
对他来说要是他儿子能接管所有财产
It seemed a fine stroke to him that his son
那可是再好不过
should step into the whole property.
我坚决反对
There I was firm.
我不会让他那该死的血统
I would not have his cursed stock
来玷污我们家的血脉
mixed with mine.
倒不是我不喜欢那孩子
Not that I had any dislike for the lad,
可是他身上流着他父亲的血
but his father's blood was in him
这就够了
and that was enough.
我立场坚定
I stood firm.
McCarthy威胁我
McCarthy threatened,
我说他用最毒辣的手段也吓不倒我
I braved him to do his worst.
我们约好在两家之间的湖边见面
We arranged to meet at the Mirror,
把事情说清楚
halfway between our two houses to talk it over.
按我说的去做
- Do as you're told.
James
James.
我听着他的话
As I listened to his talk all that was
心里所有的愤恨越来越强烈
black and bitter seemed to come upper most
他催促他儿子娶我的女儿
and he was urging his son to marry my daughter
丝毫没有顾及她的感受
with as little regard for what she might think
活活把她当成了街上卖身的妓女
as a slut from off the streets.
-我们以前就谈过这个 -按我说的去做 小子!
-We have been through all this before. -Do as I tell you, boy,
你这该死的不听话的小杂种!
you damn disobedient little bastard.
一想到我和我心爱的一切
It drove me mad to think that I
将落入这个人的魔爪
and all that I held dear
我都快疯了
should be in the power of such a man.
-这是我的生活! -我要按我的方式去过!
It's my life and I'm going to run it the way I like.
我快死了 也没什么指望了
I was a dying and desperate man.
如果我能让这张邪恶的嘴巴永远闭上
If I could silence that foul tongue I could still
那我还能挽救我 和我的家庭在这个溪谷里的名声
save me and my family's reputation in this valley.
给我滚开
Get off out of it.
是我干的  福尔摩斯先生
I did it, Mr. Holmes,
再来一次 我还会这么干
and I would do it again.
虽然我罪孽深重
Deeply though I've sinned
但我也过了一辈子痛苦的日子做出了补偿
I've lived a life of martyrdom to atone for it.
如果让我的女儿
If my girl should become entangled
也经受我曾受过的痛苦
in the same meshes which held me
那我是绝对不答应的
was more than I could suffer.
我把他打倒了 心里一点也不后悔
I struck him down with no more compunction
他就是一只凶猛恶毒的野兽
than if he'd been some foul and venomous beast.
这就是事情的经过 先生们
That is the true story gentlemen
千真万确
of all that occurred.
对你的判决不是由我来做
It is not for me to judge you,
但是我希望 我们永远也不用经受这样的诱惑
but I hope that we may never expose to such temptation.
我也希望不用 先生
I pray not, sir.
我是个快要死的人了
I'm a dying man.
我患糖尿病很多年了
I've had the diabetes for years.
我的医生说 我是否能活上一个月都成问题
My doctor says it's a question  of whether I shall live a month
而我想要死在自己家里
and I'd rather die under me own roof
而不是在监狱中
than in a jail.
不会的 不过McCarthy必须获释
No, McCarthy must be got off, however.
老天助我
God help me but
不过我也不想那男孩受到伤害
I wouldn't let that young man come to harm.
我向你保证
I'll give you my word that I'd have spoken out
如果审判对他不利 我会说出真相的
if it went against him at the assizes.
很高兴听到你这样说
I'm very glad to hear you say so.
要不是为了我亲爱的女儿
I'd have spoken now
我现在就会把真相公诸于众
if it had not been for my dear girl.
这样会让她心碎的
It would break her heart.
她要是听到我被捕了 她会心碎的
It'll break her heart when she hears that I'm arrested.
不会到那个地步
It may not come to that.
我们不是警察
We're not the police.
我也不是政府的什么密探
I am no official agent.
我是应你女儿的要求来的
I'm here at your daughter's request.
-Alice? -是Alice
-Alice? -Alice.
那你打算怎么做?
Then what do you intend to do?
考虑到你的健康 我什么也不打算做
In view of your health, nothing.
你自己都意识到 你将去到更高的一级法庭(天庭)
You are yourself aware that you'll have to answer
来为你所做的事情承担后果
for your deed at a higher court than the assizes.
如果小McCarthy被宣告有罪
If young McCarthy's condemned
我将不得不公开你的供词
I shall be forced to use this confession.
要是他被判无罪 那这份供词就永远不会被人看到
If not, it will never be seen by mortal eye
而不管你是否在世 你的秘密都将是安全的
and your secret whether you be alive or dead, shall be safe.
那么再见吧
Farewell then.
在你自己要离开人世的时候
Your own deathbeds when they come
当你一想到你曾给我带来的安宁
a little bit easier for a  thought of the peace
你会死得更心安的
that you've given to mine.
噢 上帝啊 帮帮我们吧
Oh God, help us.
Turner John Stewart 于8月16日
Turner, John Stewart, 16th of August,
在Cheshire郡的Boscombe宅邸Cheshire
Boscombe Hall Cheshire.
在长期与病魔斗争后
After a long illness,
与世长辞 Alice敬爱的父亲
bravely born, beloved father of Alice.
我们可以在小McCarthy的审讯中
Well, we're free to use that confession
随意地使用那份供词了
at young McCarthy's trial.
不 绝对不要
No, by no means.
我的承诺是除非McCarthy被判有罪
My promise was it would not be used
否则我们将不会使用它
unless McCarthy is condemned
而我想我已经给出了足够的反驳理由
and I think I've given enough objections
足以确保他无罪释放
to the charge to insure his acquittal.
希望如此
Well, I hope so.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
嫁给我好吗?
Will you marry me?
好的
Yes, I will.
一起精彩案件的完美结局
A happy ending to a brilliant case.
我向你表示祝贺 福尔摩斯
I congratulate you, Holmes.
我向你表示感谢
I thank you.
我必须承认
I must admit
这个案子中有某些地方
there are certain aspects to this case,
是连我都始料不及的
which even I did not anticipate.